Finding Aid for Frank Ward Fletcher papers, 1875-1922
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Frank Ward Fletcher papers 1875-1922
Fletcher, Frank Ward, 1853-1922.
1.5 linear feet
88306 Aa 2
Alpena, Michigan, lumberman and Republican member of the Board of Regents of the University of Michigan; business and personal correspondence, University of Michigan Board of Regents correspondence, financial materials, and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Fletcher’s son Philip Kingbury Fletcher (donor no. 17 ) and came to the library in 1936. Additional material came from Fred R. Trelfa (donor no. 3 223 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Frank Ward Fletcher was born in Boston on May 16, 1853. At a young age, he moved with his parents to Detroit where he received his early education. He received his B.A. degree from the University of Michigan in 1875, then completed his education at the Boston Institute of Technology and the Columbia School of Mines. He joined his father in George N. Fletcher's extensive lumbering and mining interests in the vicinity of Alpena, Michigan. The younger Fletcher devoted his energy to increasing and developing Alpena industries, being instrumental in the organization of the Alpena Paper Co. and the Fletcher Paper Company. Politically active, Fletcher served two-terms as regent of the University of Michigan from 1894 to 1910. He did not seek a third term. He died December 18, 1922.
The Frank Ward Fletcher collection includes letters from his father George N. Fletcher concerning business and personal affairs. There are also letters received from faculty and university administrators from the period when he was a member of the Board of Regents. Miscellaneous items include a letterpress book, 1885-1899, of business letters and files of bills and receipts. Of interest are materials relating to state Republican politics, especially the elections of 1896 and 1898. The one file of photographs includes portraits of family members as well as snapshots of Fletcher and others on a boating excursion.
Subjects:
Alpena (Mich.); Elections--Michigan--1896.; Elections--Michigan--1898.; Logging--Michigan--Alpena.; Lumbering--Michigan--Alpena.; Michigan--Politics and government--1877-1898.; Michigan--Politics and government--1899-1916.; Republican Party (Mich.); University of Michigan. Board of Regents.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Fletcher family.
Contributors:
Fletcher, George N., b. 1813.; Hanna, Marcus Alonzo, 1837-1904.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Business and personal correspondence
  - 1880-1899 and 1913, 26 folders (Box 1)
    (include letter from Mark Hanna, April 1896 and from Chase S. Osborn, 1913)
- Board of Regents Files
  - 1895-1899, 10 folders (Box 1)
- Other materials
  - Letterpress book, 1885-1899 (Box 1)
  - Personal bills and receipts, 1909-1917, 10 folders (Box 1)
  - Pages from check book, 1922 (Box 1)
  - Check book stubs, 1913-1922, 4 volumes (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous pocket diaries, notebooks, etc., 1875-1922, 32 volumes (Box 2)
Related Material
The library also has a Fletcher family collection which contains personal papers of Frank W. Fletcher. Also related are records of the Fletcher, Pack and Company and the Thunder Bay Boom Company.